Jinbo Li

(+61)450460923 jinbo.l931@gmail.com

Personal statement

Main research area in Data Mining, Enjoy to explore the core concept of algorithm and ML.

EE related bachelor background, Code clean, AWS, ML, Linux and Raspberry Pi developing Experience.

Presentation lover, enjoy to exchanging views and opinions.

Employment

Algorithm engineer, Internship

FACON Technology

12.2018 - 02.2019

Develop an algorithm of wearable thermometer(using medical glue), which can predict the armpit temperature. The main functions of the algorithm:

- Judge the different product's heating state and running different sub-function.
- Provide a reliable prediction body temperature in 30s.
- Detect the motion of arm:
 - When user does not clamp the device, the sensor will be influence by air, so the readings will be lower than the true value. When the device not be clamped, the algorithm can detect it and run compensation model to get a predict value which is approximately equal to true value.

Algorithm engineer, Internship

Metsu Semiconductor Technology

07.2018 - 10.2018

Developing the diesel engine performance monitor, running ANN with edge computing implementations. The main tasks:

- Train an ANN model with data from the monitor's sensors and the state about the engine.
 - Feature engineering on gear vibration, tail gas, temperature, diesel cost, speed and more.
 - Deal with Dimension Explosion.
- Apply the trained model on Raspberry Pi 3 model B of engine state real-time detecting.

Student vise leader

HIT IT Association

03.2014 - 07.2015

• Organizing association event; Python and HTML education; Project manager of main associate business event.

Technial experience

Quora Insincere Questions Classification combine with RL(Current project)

- Classify the values of question. One idea: classify the question by the emotions when people reading them.
- GOAL: Using emotion as the trigger/reward in reinforcement learning.

Titanic: Machine Learning from Disaster

• Learned more technique about feature engineering, Such as Expand more data feature bu deal with name column.

Image classification on CIFAR-10, Cat vs Dogs

• More experience on EDA, training Alex-net on external GPU, deploy the model with javascript.

Data wrangling on Express Post

- Data visualization: Explain the feature of data, Such as: Frequency, Correlation, GPS Distribution, Price and Time
 cost trend with similar situation.
- Data wrangling: According to the EDA, generate the model, deal with the Missing value, Wrong value and Redundancy value.

Hexpod robot engineering design, hardware and software design

 Include: Mechanical structure design, force analysis, hardware design and driver, gait and motion logic, obstacle avoidance logic.

Failed Project - WeChat plugin App(a gambling calculator of match)

The stakeholder analyzing was insufficient. So our project suffered the impact from the government policy.

Education

Data science

Monash University

07.2017 - 10.2019

Master degree Main course:

Data visualization, Data wrangling, Data mining models, ML algorithms, Distributed Computing, Product Management.

Energy Engineering and Automation Heilongjiang Institute of Technology

09.2012 - 07.2016

Bachelor degree Main course:

Thermodynamics, Engineering Mechanics, PLC technology, Electrical and Electronic Technology, Network Security

Skill

Python, R, Java, JavaScrip, C, dask, numpy, pandas, Tensorflow, Pytorch, OpenCV, SQL, Mongodb, Apache Spark Matlab, Tableau, Linux, Matplotlib, seaborn, ggplot, D3.js, R shiny

Reward

- Information Technology International Merit Scholarship(2017 2019, Monash University).
- University Excellent Graduation Design, held by Heilongjiang Institute of Technology.
- Distinguished Contribution Award, held by IT developers(Heilongjiang Institute of Technology).

Jinbo Li

(+61)450460923 jinbo.l931@gmail.com

个人陈述

主研究方向为数据挖掘,热衷于探索算法及机器学习的核心数学原理。

本科背景电子工程相关,编程风格注重代码可读性,AWS,ML,Linux 和 Raspberry Pi 开发经验。 热衷演讲, 乐于交换观点和意见。

实践经历

算法工程师,实习

苏州飞康生物医药有限公司

12.2018 - 02.2019

基于公司的可穿戴式体温计开发温度预测算法。

主要功能为:

- 判断不同的产品受热状态并执行不同的子功能。
- 在30秒内提供可靠的预测体温。
- 检测手臂的动作:
 - 当用户没有正确夹紧体温计时,传感器会受到空气影响,于是产品读数会低于真实值。当此情况发生时, 算法会探测到此状态并运行一个补偿算法,然后返回一个接近真实值的预测体温值。

算法工程师,实习

芽津半导体科技(上海)有限公司

07.2018 - 10.2018

开发应用于柴油机上的检测装置,进行神经网络的边缘计算开发。

主要任务:

- 在传感器的回传数据集以及发动机状态数据上训练神经网络。
 - 对齿轮震动,尾气,温度,燃油消耗,速度等数据进行特征工程。
 - 处理维度爆炸。
- 在树莓派上部署模型并进行实时发动机状态检测。

社团副主席

黑龙江工程学院IT创业协会

03.2014 - 07.2015

• 组织社团活动以及Python和HTML的教学; 创业活动项目经理。

项目经验

Quora Insincere Questions Classification combine with RL(正在进行)

- 对Quora上的问题价值进行分类. 目前方向: 通过阅读者的情绪来进行分类。
- 最后目标: 研究情绪在强化学习中作为激励条件的可行性。

Titanic: Machine Learning from Disaster

• 习得了更多的特征工程方法,本项目最精彩之处为对姓名类进行更为细致的特征工程。

CIFAR-10图像分类, Cat vs Dogs

• 掌握了更多EDA技巧, 在外接显卡上训练 Alex-net, 用javascript部署模型。

对快递数据集进行Data Wrangling

- 数据可视化: 解释数据特征, 例如: 频率, 相关性, GPS 分布, 在相似条件下价格随运送时间的变化趋势。
- Data wrangling: 根据EDA的结论, 生成价格—其他特征的预测模型, 处理缺失值, 错误值和冗余值。

六足机器人工程及程序设计

• 包括: 机械结构设计,受力分析,硬件设计及驱动,步态和动作逻辑设计,避障逻辑设计。

失败项目 - 微信小程序(比赛赔率计算器)

• 利益相关者分析上存在不足,导致项目因为相关政策问题而提前终止。

教育经历

数据科学,硕士

莫那什大学

07.2017 - 10.2019

Data visualization, Data wrangling, Data mining models, ML algorithms, Distributed Computing, Product Management.

能源工程及其自动化,学十

黑龙江工程学院

09.2012 - 07.2016

热力学,工程力学,PLC技术,电工电子技术,网络安全等。

技能

Python, R, Java, JavaScrip, C, dask, numpy, pandas, Tensorflow, Pytorch, OpenCV, SQL, Mongodb, Apache Spark Matlab, Tableau, Linux, Matplotlib, seaborn, ggplot, D3.js, R shiny

奖项

- Information Technology International Merit Scholarship(2017 2019, Monash University).
- 黑龙江工程学院校级优秀毕业设计奖,黑龙江工程学院IT创业协会杰出贡献奖。